嘿  看我们运气多好
Hey, We are so in luck!
特雷盖说  地下室的东西我们随便拿
Treeger said that we could have all this cool stuff from the basement.
等一下
Wait right there.
不  我要划向远方
Oh, no. I'm paddling away.
我们真的要这些生锈的废物  免费拿
Really?! We get all this rusty crap for free?
还有些爆竹呢  没点过的
This and a bunch of bubble wrap. And, some of it is not even popped!
我们真算得白人垃圾
Could we be more white trash?
《老友记》  第四季  第03集  爱的手铐
Friends S04E03  The one with the "cuffs"
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
我真是绝望透了
How desperate am I?
幸好钱德不在这儿  谁也惨不过他
Good thing Chandler's not here, he always wins at this game.
我刚刚告诉我妈   帮她的晚会准备食物
I just told my Mom I'd cater a party for her.
为什么这样做   因为我需要钱
How come? -Because I need the money
而且我那点仅存的自尊  不要也罢
and I thought that it'd be a great way to get rid of that last little schmidgen of self-respect.
别这样  这是一件好事
Come on, I think this is a good thing.
老妈若不是觉得你厨艺精湛  才不会雇你呢
I don't think Mom would've hired you if she didn't think you were good at what you do.
你犯不着替她说好话   她又听不见
You don't have to stick up for her. She can't hear you.
你有水果汁吗
Do you have any juice?
只有泡菜
Just pickle.
瑞秋  昨天很有趣  我在街上碰见乔安娜了
Hey, Rach, funny story. I, bumped into Joanna on the street yesterday.
我的老板  乔安娜  很惨吧
My boss, Joanna? That must have been awkward.
不  实际上  她只是问我是否想一起喝一杯
Well, no, actually she uh, asked me if I wanted to get a drink.
你没答应她吧
You, you didn't say 'Yes' to that did you?
没有  没有
No! No!
嘿  瑞秋
Hello, Rachel.
起初我没答应
Well, not at first.
她在这里做什么
What is she doing here?
上次你跟她约会以后  还说她是个反应迟钝的笨女人
I don't understand! Last time you went out with her you said she was a 'big, dull dud.'
我过早对她下结论了
Well, I think I judged her too quickly,
现在我跟她可以做进一步的发展
and this time we were able to take the relationship to the next level.
上次我差点被开除  你必须跟她绝交  立刻
Well, last time I almost got fired. You must end it, you must end it now!
我又不是天天有艳遇
Oh, come on! It's not like this is an everyday occurrence for me!
通常我都是独处的
I mean usually I'm pretty much just in there by myself.
钱德  答应我
Chandler! Promise me.
跟她断交
you will end this now.
好吧   我答应   谢谢
Okay, I promise, I'll end it. Thank you.
希望你知道  我为了你牺牲很大
I hope you know what I'm giving up for you
她可不光是你的老板而己  懂吗
because she's not just the boss in your office, if you know what I mean.
抱歉  我只是了解他的意思
Sorry. I knew what he meant.
大厨进展的如何了
How's the hired help?
很顺利  法式咸派快好了
Doing great. Quiches are coming along.
这是什么  蓝色指甲油
What's this? Blue nail polish?
我觉得很好看
Yeah, I thought it was cute.
你祖母死后  我们发现时  她的手就这样
Ha. It's what your grandmother's hands looked like when we found her.
我想问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
为什么你要雇我
Why did you hire me?
理查德一直说他晚会的派对餐点很棒
Well Richard raved about the food at his party...
当然  那时你和他睡过
of course you were sleeping with him.
而且我听说  在那个女同性恋的婚礼上
Then I heard the food at that lesbian
你的菜也大受欢迎
wedding was very nice.
我假定你没和那里的什么人睡过
I assume you weren't sleeping with anybody there.
所以  我认为你可能有两把刷子
Though, at least that would be something.
天啊  你听到了吗
Oh, my God! Did you hear that?
她雇我是因为  她认为我很优秀
She hired me because she thinks I'm good.
我没听见
I didn't hear that.
她不是可怜我
Oh yeah, she didn't hire me out of pity.
不是想在朋友面前刁难我
it wasn't so she could pick on me in front of her friends,
她是真的觉得我行
she actually thinks I'm good.
喔   如果你是个同性恋就太酷了
Wow! And hey, it's cool if you're a lesbian!
下午好  你是一家之主吗
Good afternoon, are you the decision maker of the house?
你有大百科全书吗
Do you currently own a set of encyclopedias?
没有  你可以查查分类广告  卖什么的都有
No, but try the classifieds. People sell everything in there.
实际上  我不是要买  我是要卖
Actually, I'm not buying. I'm selling.
我想问你一个问题
Let me ask you one question.
朋友们聊天的时候
Do your friends ever have a conversation...
你只能跟着点头   却搞不懂他们在说什么
and you just nod along, even though you're not really sure what they're talking about?
我告诉你  这是违反宪法的
I'm telling you, it's totally unconstitutional.
没错  完全同意
I hear you. Yeah it is. I totally agree.
我觉得他应该得诺贝尔奖
I think he deserves a Nobel Prize.
才怪
No.
很像阿尔冈昆族小孩的桌子
It was like the Algonquin kids table.
抱歉  对不起
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
这两分半钟   你什么也没有说
You haven't said anything for about two minutes.
你有兴趣吗
Are you at all interested?
有  有… 进来
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, oh, yeah. Come on in.
怪了  什么
That's weird. What?
你的指甲
Your nails.
我知道  我从不戴假指甲的
I know, I never wear fake ones.
我怕咬指甲被我妈抱怨
I just did it so my Mom wouldn't give me grief about me biting them.
不  我的意思是  你现在只有九个指甲
No, I meant that it's weird that you only have nine now.
天啊
Oh, my God!
等一下
Wait a minute.
刚才还是十个
I had them when I put...
天啊  在咸派饼里
Oh, my God! It's in the quiche!
天啊  别着急
Oh, my God! Okay, don't panic.
我现在就去商店  帮你买一套新指甲
I'm gonna go to the store, I'm gonna get you another set of nails.
神不知鬼不觉  你看起来还是很美
No one's gonna know, and you're gonna look great.
但是问题是  他们会吃到那只的
Oh. Oh, it's because they're gonna eat... That's the problem.
亲爱的  不要咬你的指甲
Honey, don't bite your nails.
好吧  别惊慌
Okay, please don't freak out.
不过有个咸派里  有我的一片蓝指甲
but, there's a blue fingernail in one of the quiche cups.
谁也不知道是哪一个杯子
And there's no way to know which one.
找到指甲可以中大奖
And whoever finds it wins the prize!
我没惊慌
I'm not freaking out.
那你笑什么  没事  你爸输给我5美元
Then why are you laughing? It's nothing, it's just that now your Father owes me five dollars.
什么  你打赌我会掉一个指甲吗
What? You bet I'd lose a nail?
别傻了   我打赌我会用上这个
Don't be silly. I just bet that I'd need these.
冰冻宽面条
Frozen lasagnas? Mm.
你赌我会搞砸
You bet that I'd screw up?
"你雇我是因为我很优秀"  都是假的...
So all that stuff about hiring me because I was good was...
不  不  不  那是真的
No, that was all true.
准备备用食物  只是怕你又"很莫妮卡"
This was just in case you "pulled a Monica."
你答应过外恩博格教授   不再这么说了
You promised Dr. Weinburg, you'd never use that phrase.
拜托  有点幽默感嘛
Oh honey, come on, have a sense of humour
你总是不懂得自嘲
you've never been able to laugh at yourself.
没错
That's right.Ha, ha.
我妈从没信任过我  好好笑
My mom doesn't have any faith in me. Oh, that's hilarious.
我不觉得好笑
I don't get it.
不   我信任你
No. I have faith.
不   你只是有烤宽面条
No. You have lasagnas!
报废的咸派烤好了
The ruined quiches are ready.
（百货公司）
怎么没有...分手的感觉
It just doesn't...feel like we're breaking up.
的确分手了  我好伤心
No, we are. I'm sad.
好吧
Okay!
说
Yes.
不能等到明天吗  好吧
Can't you wait until tomorrow? All right.
难以置信
Unbelievable!
谢谢
Thanks.
不是  我得去见我的老板
No, no, that was my boss. I have to go.
你做什么
What are you doing?
我穿衣服  为什么
I'm getting dressed. Why?
我光溜溜走出去  会有人朝我扔东西
When I walk outside naked people throw garbage at me.
等一下  给你看些东西
Wait. I want to show you something.
什么
What is it?
别人给我的一个小道具
Just a little gag gift somebody gave me.
把手并拢
Put your hands together.
你不是我的老板
You're not the boss of me.
你是
Yeah, you are.
好调皮
Saucy!
2分钟后我就回来
I'll be back in two minutes.
你就这样离开我
You're going to leave me like this?
你就乖乖地坐在这里等我  感觉让人兴奋
Knowing you're here waiting for me. I think that's kind of exciting.
好的  但如果你不能马上回来
Okay. But if you don't come back soon...
我也不能怎么样
there's pretty much nothing I can do about it!
我给你带了蛋白杏仁饼干
I brought you back a macaroon!
太好了  我会把它贴在屁股上
Oh great! I'll keep it in my butt with your nose.
奇怪  她把门锁上了
That's weird. She locked the door.
你知道为什么吗  里面有圣诞节奖金名单
You know why? She's got the Christmas bonus list in there.
我早晨看见她在写
I saw her working on it this morning.
好吧  你发誓不告诉别人
Okay, swear you won't tell.
马克离开前给了我一把乔安娜办公室的钥匙
but when Mark left he gave me a key to Joanna's office.
你想看清单吗  想
You want to see the list? Yeah.
嗨
Hi.
你们好吗
How are you?
你好  乔安娜...
Hello, Joanna...
的办公室
...'s office.
真的很抱歉  我可能要多呆一小会儿
I'm really sorry but I may be a little while longer.
有多小  几个小时  这太可怕了
How little? A couple of hours, I feel awful.
听着   这一点都不好玩  马上给我回来
Look, this isn't funny! You get back here right now!
我没办法   为什么
I can't! Why not?
我正在我老板的车里
I'm in my boss's car!
什么  进隧道了
What?  Tunnel!
什么事
What?
瑞秋  请进来一下
Rachel, could I see you for a moment?
可以  现在的情况是...
Okay, here's the situation...
手拷的钥匙在门的后面
The keys to the cuffs are on the back of the door.
你可以乖乖
Could you be a doll...
把钥匙拿来给我开锁吗
and grab them and scoot on over here and unlock me?
顺便说一下  你的长裤套装很可爱
And on a totally different subject, that is a lovely pantsuit.
你发誓你和她分手了
You promised you would break up with her.
我是和她分手了  只不过她分得很狂野
I did break up with her! She just took it really, really well!
你都没想过  这样会破坏我的事业吗
And the fact that you were jeopardising my career never entered your mind?!
我想过啊
It did enter my mind.
但是情况有变   打开手铐
But then something happened that made it shoot right out.
钱德  你作茧自缚  你自己想办法
You know what Chandler, you got yourself into those cuffs, you get yourself out of them.
别... 我开不了手拷
No..I can't get myself right out of them!
你把我跟 "脱逃大师钱德" 搞混了
You must have me confused with the "Amazing Chandler"!
快点  你必须帮我
Come on, you have to unlock me,
她要好几个小时后才能回来  我很冷  而且
she could be gone for hours, and I'm cold, and...
钱德  好吧  我帮你
Ugh! Chandler. All right! This is it!
不准你再见她
Never see her again.
永远
Never!
不准再进这个办公室  好的
You never come into this office again! Fine!
把我的随身听还给我
You give me back my Walkman!
我...从没借过
I...never borrowed your Walkman.
那是我搞丢了  你买一个给我
Well, then I lost it. You buy me one!
成交  我们现在就离开  这感觉太好了
You got it! Here we go! Come on! This is great!
很疼吗
Does it hurt?
不  我经常看见手拷被打开后会大松一口气
No, I just always see guys doing this when they get handcuffs taken off them.
我可爱的裤子
Hello, sweet pants!
等一下  你打算怎么跟乔安娜交代
Wait a minute! What are you gonna tell Joanna?
交代什么
About what?
她看见你不在了  就知道是我放你走的
When she sees that you're gone, she's gonna know that I let you out,
我会被炒鱿鱼的
and that I was in here, and I'm gonna get fired!
我会编个故事   我很擅长说慌
I'll make something up! I'm good at lying!
实际上我借过你的随身听
I actually did borrow your Walkman!
我无法解释  她知道我有她办公室的钥匙
No, there's nothing to make up, she's gonna know that I have a key to her office.
我得把你铐回去
I've got to get you locked up back the way you were!
噢  想都别想
Oh, I don't think so.
这样好多了
Well, this is much better.
乔伊  这个人很有意思
So, here's somebody interesting, Joey.
你知道梵高吗
What do you know about Van Gogh?
他割了自己的耳朵  还有呢
He cut off his ear. And?
没了
I'm out.
他画了这个
He painted that.
画得真好
That's pretty nice.
我还认为割掉自己耳朵  是他大蠢了
I thought he cut off his ear because he sucked.
还有什么  让我看看
What else you got in there? Let's see...
教皇住在哪里  森林里
Where does the Pope live? In the woods.
不  等等  那是开玩笑的
No wait-wait, that's the joke answer.
其实  他住在梵蒂冈
Actually, it's Vatican City.
你知道硫化橡胶吗
Now, what do you know about vulcanized rubber?
节育用品
Spock's birth control.
你需要这套书
You need these books.
嘿   嗨
Hey.  Hi.
这是你以前的房间
This used to be your room?
哇  你童年时身材一定很好
Wow. Oh, you must have been in really good shape as a kid.
我太白痴了
I'm such an idiot!
我居然以为她会改变
I can't believe I thought she could change.
谁关心你妈怎么想
Well, who cares what your Mom thinks?
无非就是"很莫妮卡"
So you "pulled a Monica."
很好  我很高兴你也这么说
Good, I'm glad that's catching on.
这不一定是坏话  我们可以当它是褒义
No but, why does that have to be a bad thing. Just change what it means.
去证明你妈是错的
You know? Go down there and prove your Mother wrong.
把你该干的话做好  我们把那叫做"很莫妮卡"
Finish the job you were hired to do, and we'll call that "pulling a Monica."
什么
What?
如果一个孩子成绩得了A  他父母就会说：
Okay, if a kid gets straight A's, his parents would say,
"耶  他很莫妮卡"
"Yeah, he pulled a Monica." You know?
消防队员救了一个孩子  人们就会说"耶  他很莫妮卡"
Or a fireman saves a baby, and they go, "Yeah I know, he pulled a Monica."
当有人打了一个全垒打  播音员就说"太棒了"
Or someone hits a homerun and the announcer says, "Yeah, that one's outta here."
有些事是不会变的
Because some things don't change.
好吧  我现在下楼去
All right. I'll go down there.
我不端烤宽面条  我要端我做的菜出去
But, I'm not gonna serve the lasagna. I'm gonna serve something I make.
我的乳房还真强壮呢
My breasts are really strong.
钱德  我必须把你锁回去  我不能失去这份工作
Chandler, please, I have to get you locked up back the way you were, I am sooo gonna lose my job!
她的办公室是非常保密的
She's very private about her office!
现在我知道原因了
Now I know why!
反正你都会有麻烦  明白吗
Look, you're in trouble either way! Okay?
她回来看见我被锁在这边
If she comes back and sees me locked to this instead of the chair...
知道你进来过  还不如让我走
she's gonna know you were in here. So you might as well just let me go.
我帮你打扫一个月浴室   还是洗不干净
What if I clean your bathroom for a month? It still wouldn't be clean.
我只是想要自由
All I want is my freedom.
帮你脚底按摩一个月   自由啊
Foot rubs for a month! Freedom!
帮你把所有照片都收到相册里   我还是只想要自由啊
I'll take all of your photos and put them into photo albums! Freedom! I want my freedom!
为什么你不能帮我  索菲  救我
Why won't you hear me! Sophie, help me!
索菲  坐
Sophie, sit!
天哪  你不能冷静下吗
No! God, would you just calm down!
我只想说最后一遍
I'm gonna say this for the last time.
你能不能...
Would you please just...
想不到呕吐也有这么多学问
There's a lot I didn't know about vomit.
稍等
In a minute.
乔伊  怎么样
So what do you say? Joe?
你只要花1200块  就可以得到一整套百科全书
You get the whole set of encyclopedias for twelve hundred dollars
平均一本才50元
That works out to just 50 bucks a book.
1200块
Twelve hundred dollars?
你认为我会有1200块吗
You think I have $1200?
这些天我一直窝在家里
I'm home during the day...
我的客厅里摆着凉椅
and I got patio furniture in my living room.
你博览群书却没学到某些常识
I guess there's a few things you don't get from book learnin'.
好吧  你能凑出多少
Well, what can you swing?
分期付款卖给我如何  每月付零元
How about zero down and zero a month for a long, long time?
你什么都没有
You don't have anything?
想看看我有什么  好的
You want to see what I got? Okay!
我有巧克力软糖
I've got a baby Tootsie Roll...
一张电影票  钥匙  面巾纸
a movie stub, keys, a Kleenex...
石头
a rock...
还有个小兵人
and an army man.
好  了解了  耽误你了
Okay, I get the picture. Thanks for your time.
还有五十块钱
And a fifty.
这一定是钱德的裤子
These must be Chandler's pants.
如果是50元的话   你就能拥有一本书了
For 50 bucks, you can get one book!
你想要哪本 A B C
What will it be? A? B? C?
我想要V那本
I think I'm gonna stick with the V.
我想看看坏孩子是怎么回事
I want to see how this bad boy turns out. Heh.
我帮你打点圣诞礼物  不用
I, will buy and wrap all of your Christmas gifts. No.
我每天早晨给你榨鲜橙汁
I...I'll squeeze you fresh orange juice every morning!
带水果肉的吗  有
With extra pulp? Yeah.
不用了
No!
我想到了
I've got it!
你才没辙呢
You don't have it.
我胜券在握
I have so got it!
这件事会传出去  挡也挡不住
There's gonna be rumours about this, there's no way to stop it.
索菲知道  莫妮卡和菲比也知道
Sophie knows, Monica and Phoebe know.
她们怎么会知道  我给她们打电话
How do Monica and Phoebe know? I called them.
如果她们问我看见了什么
And when they ask me what I saw...
我会非常大方
I can be very generous...
或者守口如瓶
or very stingy.
继续
Go on.
我可以让你成为一个传奇
I can make you a legend.
我可以让你成为当今的"米尔顿·伯乐(谐星)"
I can make you this generatiors Milton Berle.
米尔顿可了不得... 他都无法同你媲美
And Milton erle has a... Not compared to you.
客人们碰都没碰宽面条
They're not even touching the lasagna!
真的吗  他们喜欢你的砂锅料理
Really? Oh, they love your casserole.
太棒了
Yes!
很难相信  刚才还只有一些原材料
It's hard to believe that just a little while ago this was nothing but ingredients.
看来大家都喜欢你的菜
Well, everyone seems to be enjoying your dish.
你呢
And you?
我想它是...
I thought it was...
十分可口
quite tasty.
要是大家都喜欢  你也喜欢
So if everyone liked it, and you liked it...
那就代表我成功了  那你就是个...
that would make this a success. Which would make you…
贱人
A bitch?
我想说“你就错了”  但你的说法也行
Well, I was going for "wrong", but we can use your word.
我错了
Yes, well, I was wrong.
我必须告诉你
And I have to say...
今天你给我留下了非常深刻的印象
you really impressed me today.
你可以说她  "很莫妮卡"
You might even say that she "pulled a Monica."
她不知道  我们已经把它意思改变了
She doesn't know we switched it.
下次你帮我办外烩
And the next time you cater for me...
冷箱里只会有冰
there will be nothing but ice in the freezer.
这是很大的鼓励
Well, That really means a lot.
妈  别咬指甲
Mom, don't bite your nails!
（中央咖啡厅）
哈罗  嗨
Hello. Hey.
嗨  钱德
Hello, Chandler.
我爱你
I love you.
怎么了
What's going on?
不  他才不会
No, he doesn't!
拖了两小时
Two hours, that lasted.
所以你跟乔安娜分手了吗
So did you break up with Joanna?
应该是吧
I think so.
幸好她跟维苏威一样爆炸之前  你就闪了
Well, it's good thing you got out when you did, before she blew up like that Vesuvius.
像火山  对
The volcano? Yeah.
是啊  像火山一样  那些火山岩还真可怕
Yeah. And speaking of volcanoes, man are they a violent igneous rock formation.
什么
What?
熔岩乱喷  热灰乱飞
Oh yeah, lava spewing, hot ash,
不过有些是休眠火山
of course some are dormant.
怎么突然聊起火山来了
Why are you talking about volcanoes all of the sudden?
那我们聊聊其他的
Well, we can talk about something else.
你们想聊什么  活体解剖
What do you want to talk about? Vivisection?
输精管
The Vasdeferens?
越战
The Vietnam War?
有谁看过韩战的记录片吗
Did anybody see that-that documentary on the Korean War?
韩国真是个美丽的国度
Korea's a beautiful country.
命运却好悲惨   是啊
With such a sad history. Yeah.
姓"金"的人可真多
Could there be more Kims?
谁在外面  是我  早上好
Who's out there? It's me, Good morning.
瑞秋  你能进来一下吗
Rachel, could you come in here for a moment, please?
好  没问题  嗯  没有你要的那种百吉饼
Yeah, sure. they didn't have poppy seed bagels,
所以我买了芝麻…天哪
so I have sesame...Oh, my word!
我似乎有一些小麻烦
I seem to have had a slight office mishap.
你能把门后的钥匙给我吗
Could you please get the key off the back of the door for me.
好  好的  当然好
Yeah, yeah! Okay!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
你能告诉钱德   我们这次绝对是分手了
You tell your friend Chandler that we're definately broken up this time.
好的
Okay.